g.26
Ukrainian Historical and Educational Center of NJ Archives
- Parish records, 1915-1967; Series 6.
  - St. Michael parish (Scranton, Penn.) choir book (Box 18, Box 14)
    "Choir directors book" - scores and texts of liturgical music for the Divine Liturgy of St. John Chrysostom.
- Address books, notebooks, and diary, Series 7.
  - Address book, likely late 1920s (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Diary, 1928 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    Small pocket diary with addresses, business cards, and some diary entries.
  - Address book, likely late 1930s (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Notebook, undated (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Address book, likely 1960s (Box 18, Folder 19-20)
    Inserted materials have been moved to separate folder.
  - Notebook, undated (Box 19, Folder 1-2, Oversize 8)
    Notebook containing fragments of text, primarily on religious and spiritual topics. Some of these may be original writings, but many appear to have been copied out of books or other publications. Also included folded-in newspaper clippings, cards, and other materials. These have been moved to separate folders.
- Photographs, 1914-1970s; Series 8.; 0.5 Linear feet
  Arranged in two files chronologically by date or inferred date (for unlabeled photographs), except for panorama photos and recent photocopies, which form their own separate file. Inferred dates are extremely uncertain, therefore researchers searching for mid-century items should consult both files.
  Some folders include related newspaper clippings.
  - 1914-circa 1940, 12 folders (Oversize 9-11, Box 20, Folder 1-8, Box 19, Folder 3)
  - circa 1940-1970s, 9 folders (Oversize 12, Box 20, Folder 9-10, Box 19, Folder 4-9)
  - Panorama photographs, 1918-circa 1950 (Oversize 13)
  - Photocopies of photographs (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Ephemera and newspaper clippings, 1915-1970s; Series 9.; 0.5 Linear feet
  Contains ephemera and newspaper clippings that could not be associated with another series based on original order, as well as religious tracts, holy cards, and similar material.
  - Ephemera and near-print materials, 1915-1960s (bulk 1930s-1960s); 4 folders (Box 21, Folder 1-3, Box 19, Folder 11-12)
    Concert programs, flyers, pamphlets, brochures, and similar materials.
  - Newspaper clippings, 1920s-1970s; 3 folders (Box 21, Folder 4-6)
  - Prayer books, tracts, and holy cards, circa 1915-circa 1960; 2 folders (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
- Books and other published materials, Series 10.; 9.75 Linear feet
  - Commemorative books, 1933-1974
    Publications created by parishes or the UOC of USA to commemorate major events or anniversaries. They typically contain historical narratives, photographs, advertisements, and (in some cases) event programs.
    - St. Vladimir parish (Cleveland, Oh.), 1933, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - St. Andrew parish (Boston, Mass.), 1958 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - St. Volodymyr parish (Chicago, Ill.), 1966 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Fr. Joseph Zelechivsky 50th anniversary of priesthood, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Anniversary of the 1921 All-Ukrainian Church Council, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - St. Vladimir parish (Parma, Oh.), 1974 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - UOC of USA almanacs, 1954-1955 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Annual publications of the Ukrainian Orthodox Church of the USA containing a liturgical calendar and articles on religious and Ukrainian historical and cultural topics. The calendar portion of these issues contain handwritten annotations.
  - Proceedings of the Convention of the Russian Orthodox Mission (Cleveland, Oh.), 1919 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Periodicals, 1930-1972 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Individual issues of periodicals, including "Dlia sil's'koho zhinotstva" (Kolomyia, 1933), "Ukrains'kyi natsionalist" (1935), "Ukrainian Orthodox League Bulletin" (1953), "The Word" (1961), "Lemko" (Cleveland, 1930), "Zumbrcani napred" (Chicago, 1935), "Holos Bratstva" (Trenton, NJ, 1958), "Ukrainian Orthodox Word" (1961, 1972), and "Ukrains'kyi Vistnyk" (1949-1950, 1954-1955).
  - Books, 9.5 Linear feet (Box 23, Box 27-28, Box 24-26)
    Volumes from Fr. Gregory's library, including books on religion, theology, history, literature, Latin theology textbooks that he may have used as a seminarian, liturgical books, Bibles, dictionaries and reference books, and primary-level textbooks for Ukrainian language instruction. A number of the books are inscribed by the author or as presentations to Fr. Gregory from various individuals or parish organizations.
    - Items found between pages of books (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Realia, Series 11. (Box 29, Box 30)
  Contains objects owned by Fr. Gregory, including items presented to him; liturgical and ritual items (chrismatories, altar bells, etc.); icons and crucifixes; Cyrillic typewriter; and similar objects.
- Photocopies, Series 12.; 1.25 Linear feet (Box 31)
  Contains photocopies, primarily of the professional papers of Series 1, that were made by Elaine Chomicky White. It has not been verified whether the originals of all the items in this series are contained in the other series of this collection.
  Arranged in approximate chronological order, as boxed by Elaine Chomicky White.